Register to the Paul Hindemith Collection
Yale University Music Library
The Paul Hindemith Collection
1901-1993
MSS 47
Yale University Music Library
27
(43 boxes)
Music, correspondence and other papers, photographs, and additional materials by and about the German composer Paul Hindemith (1895-1963).
Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963
Conditions Governing Access
The Papers are open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment. Some of the materials may be stored at the Library's off-campus shelving facility, so researchers should allow at least two business days to have the appropriate boxes paged.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Paul Hindemith Collection was assembled and curated by Luther Noss from 1964 to 1993. In 1993 the Collection was transferred to the Music Library of Yale University.
Arrangement
In 13 series as follows: I. Materials Relating to Hindemith's Compositions. II. Speeches, Writings and Teaching Materials. III. Collegium Musicum. IV. Additional Concerts and Teaching Materials. V. Correspondence and Journals. VI. Articles about Paul Hindemith. VII. Biographical Materials. VIII. Photographs and Drawings. IX. Personal Correspondence. X. Miscellaneous Materials XI. Holograph Materials. XII. Oversize Items. XIII. Sound Recordings.
Scope and Contents
The Paul Hindemith Collection brings together primary and secondary source materials which document the life and career of Paul Hindemith, particularly his years in the United States (1940-1953). The Collection holds holographs of 14 compositions by Hindemith, including the Lilacs Requiem and the concertos for clarinet, horn, and trumpet and bassoon. The Collection also holds secondary materials (programs, notes, and reviews) for nearly all of Hindemith's compositions, as well as extensive material relating to Hindemith's classroom teaching and the Yale Collegium Musicum. Additional materials include correspondence between Paul and Gertrud Hindemith and colleagues, friends, and music publishers; photographs and drawings; articles about Hindemith; and miscellaneous materials.
Biographical / Historical
Paul Hindemith (1895-1963) was born in Hanau, Germany. A prodigious child violinist, he left school early to study at the Hoch Conservatory in Frankfurt-am-Main. As a teenager he was already a professional string quartet performer and soon became leader of the Frankfurt Opera orchestra, under the direction of Ludwig Rottenberg, whose daughter, Gertrud, later became Mrs. Hindemith.
Hindemith studied composition under Bernhard Sekles and Arnold Mendelssohn and soon established himself at the forefront of the post World War I avant-garde. When the Nazis came to power in the 1930s, his music was banned, but not before he was firmly established as a distinguished teacher of composition at the Berlin Hochschule. Since his wife had a Jewish father, he decided to seek another residence, going first to Switzerland and in 1940 to the USA, joining the faculty of the Yale University School of Music, where he remained until his official departure for Europe in 1953.
The Paul Hindemith Collection at Yale University was established in 1964 and was under the supervision/curatorship of Prof. Luther Noss from its inception to 1993. The Collection is primarily a repository for secondary documents relating to the composer's life and work in the United States. The initial gathering of materials was implemented by a weekend commemorative concert series at the University in 1964, following soon upon the death of the composer. At that time many associates sent materials for exhibition purposes, after which much was acquired by the Collection, either as gifts or purchases.
Yale's Paul Hindemith Collection has enjoyed a close association with the Paul Hindemith Foundation, a private and nonprofit Swiss corporation that holds title to the entire Hindemith estate by the bequest of the composer's wife, Gertrud Hindemith, and the Paul Hindemith institute in Frankfurt-am-Main which is subsidized by the Foundation. Yale's Collection has been strengthened significantly by copies from the Frankfurt archives of all the correspondence and other accounts left by Paul and Gertrud Hindemith that relate to their experiences in the United States. In addition, there are copies of correspondence dating back to 1917 and forward to 1965. This time frame exceeds the actual period of 1937 (the year of Hindemith's first concert tour of the USA) to 1953 (his return to Europe) and his death in 1963.
The Collection contains a profusion of newspaper and periodical articles, clippings, concert reviews, and programs; reports from American and foreign newspapers; many private Journal entries; voluminous business correspondence with B. Schott's Söhne, Mainz, and Associated Music Publishers, Inc., New York, Schott's American agent; and personal correspondence with prospective and former students, colleagues, and friends. Its holdings also include many original drawings- made by the composer while living in New Haven, Connecticut, and many photographs of him and his wife: at home, in action - teaching, conducting, composing, with students and colleagues, and formal portraits.
Original holographs are few but significant, comprising a câche of concertos written here: Concerto for Clarinet and orchestra for Benny Goodman; Concerto for Horn and Orchestra; Concerto for Trumpet, Bassoon, and String Orchestra; Sonate Ober alten Volkslieder (XXX.) for organ; sketches for Thema mit vier Variationen, a.k.a. The Four Temperaments; pièces d'occasions known only to the participants, typically American songs, and the entire score of "When lilacs last in the dooryard bloom'd."
As complete as possible is the documentation of the Collegium Musicum performances of late medieval, Renaissance, and baroque music under Paul Hindemith's direction at Yale and Harvard Universities. Also included are the repeated performances at the Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York, with programs, lists of personnel, working copies of the music, reviews, accountings, etc.
The post-WW2 controversy brought about by the vitriolic written attacks of Theodor Adorno is well covered, including many defenses by peers and former students. In addition, virtually everything published in German has been translated into English by Prof. Noss, comprising all the prefaces to the Gesamtausgabe and the many articles contained in the Hindemith Jahrbücher. Even the libretti of the operas and German song texts are available in English. Without the years of dedication and devotion by Professor Noss to the task of collecting, filing, ordering, translating, studying, advising, and corresponding, this collection would not exist.
Recordings of works by Paul Hindemith and those he conducted himself repose in the Yale Collection of Historical Sound Recordings and are not listed in this register.
The Paul Hindemith Collection greatly enriches the Yale University Music Library's extensive collection of composers, papers, including those of Charles Ives, Virgil Thomson, Kurt Weill, Carl Ruggles, Horatio Parker, Richard Donovan, Quincy Porter, J. Rosamond Johnson, Lowell Mason, Henry Gilbert, Harold Rome, and Lehman Engel.
Index of COMPOSITION/LECTURE/TEXTBOOK
A Year Box/Folder
Abendständchen (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
Abendvolke (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
Acht Lieder, opus 18 (S & pf) 1920 1/27
Acht Stücke (solo fl) 1927 2/78
Amore und Psyche - Farnesina (orchestra) 1943 5/176
An eine Tote (SSATB unaccompanied) 1958 8/215
An einem Schmetterling (SSATB unaccompanied) 1958 8/215
Andante and Scherzo, opus1 (cl, hn, pf) 1914 1/2
Anecdotes for Radio (pf, cl, tpt, vn, cb) 1925 2/65
Angelus Domini apparuit (S/T & pf) 1958 5/162
Angst vorm Schwimmunterricht (boys chorus) 1930 2/101
Apparebit repentina dies (chorus & brass) 1947 6/187
Ascendente Jesu in naviculam (S/T & pf) 1943 5/162
The Atonal Cabaret - 5 pieces (pf) 1921 1/33
Ausflugskantate (voice, chorus, 4 cl) 1934 3/117
B Year Box/Folder
J. S. Bach: Heritage and Obligation (text) 1950 9/232
Bal des pendus (high/medium voice & pf) 1944 5/181
Zwei Balladen 1942 5/168,181
Bastellied (boys chorus) 1930 2/101
Bearbeitungen ausländischer Lieder (string quintet & cl) 1936 3/131
Beauty touch me (S & pf) 1955 7/209
La belle dame sans merci (voice & pf) 1942 5/168
Der Berufung (text) 1951 10/241
Birthday Canon for Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge 1949 7/200
C Year Box/Folder
Cadenzas for Mozart's vn & pf Concertos 1933 3/113
Cal, the lad of Ohio's anniversary song (B & pf) 1951 33/436
Canonic Sonata (2 fl), opus 31 no. 3 1923 1/51
Eight Canons, opus 45 (2-part chorus, strings ad lib) 1928 2/83
Cardillac, opus 39 (opera) 1926 2/66
Cardillac (revised version) (opera) 1952 7/204
Canticle to Hope - see Ite, angeli veloces 1953 7/206
C'est de la côte d'Adam (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
Six Chansons (SATB unaccompanied) 1939 4/149
Drei Chöre (male chorus unaccompanied) 1939 4/146
Chorlieder für Knaben 1930 2/101
La cigale el la fourmi (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
Collection of Freshly-laid Piano Eggs 1926 2/70
Collegium Musicum concerts 1943-60 11/247-264
A Composer's World (text) 1952 9/233
A Concentrated Course in Traditional Harmony (text) 1942-43 9/227
...Traditional Harmony, part 2 (text) 1949 43,9/238
Concerto (cl & orchestra) 1947 6/188
Concerto (hn & orchestra) 1949 6/195
Concerto (org & orchestra) 1963 8/222
Concerto (pf & orchestra) 1945 6/183
Concerto (pf & orchestra) for the Left hand, opus 29 1923 1/47
Concerto (tpt, bsn, string orchestra) 1949 7/199
Concerto - Der Schwanendreher (va & small orchestra) 1935 3/123
Concerto (vc & orchestra) in E-flat, opus 3 1916 1/4
Concerto (vc & orchestra) 1940 4/159
Concerto (vn & orchestra) 1939 4/147
Concerto (solo wdwnds, hp, orchestra) 1949 6/196
Concerto for Orchestra, opus 38 1925 2/64
[see also Kammermusik/Konzertmusik/Konzertstück]
The Craft of Musical Composition, parts 1-2 (text) 1937-39 9/225
The Craft..., revision for part 2 (2-part writing) 1951 9/226
The Craft..., part 3 (3-part writing) 1949 9/231
The Craft..., part 3 1949 14/277-280
The Craft..., part 4 (4-part writing) 14/281
Cum descendisset Jesus (S/T & pf) 1960 5/162
Cum factus esset Jesus (S/T & pf) 1959 5/162
Cum natus esset (S/T & pf) 1941 5/162
Cupid and Psyche Overture - Farnesina (orchestra) 1943 5/176
Custos, quid de nocte - see Ite, angeli veloces 1955 7/206
D Year Box/Folder
Der Dämon - orchestra suite 1922 1/45
Der Dämon, opus 28 (dance pantomime) 1922 1/44
Dances (pf), opus 19 1920 1/28
David's Song of Triumph - see Ite, angeli veloces 1955 7/206
Defuncto Herode (S/T & pf) 1958 5/162
Demands on Musical Amateurs (text) 1930 9/237
The Demon on the Gibbet (male chorus) 1949 7/197
Des todes Tod, opus 23a (female voice, 2 vn, 2 vc) 1922 1/34
The devil a monk would be (SSATB unaccompanied) 1937 3/132
Dicebat Jesus scribus et pharisaeis (S/T & pf) 1959 5/162
Dixit Jesus Petro (S/T & pf) 1959 5/162
The Doe (SATB unaccompanied) 1939 4/149
Drei Chöre (male chorus unaccompanied) 1939 4/146
Drei leichte Stücke in 1st position (vc & pf) 1938 4/140
Drei Lieder (Nietzsche) (voice & pf) 1939 4/155
Drei Stücke/Etuden (2 vn) 1931 2/105
Dreizehn Motetten (S/T & pf) 1940-60 5/162
Du musst dir alles geben (male chorus unaccompanied) 1930 2/99
Du Zweifel (SSATB unaccompanied) 1958 8/215
Duette (va & vc) 1934 3/116
E Year Box/Folder
Eau qui se presser (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
Echo (S & pf) 1942-44 5/171
Eight Canons, opus 45 (2-part chorus, strings ad lib) 1928 2/83
Ein Jäger aus Kurpfalz, opus 45 (strings & winds) 1928 2/84
Eine lichte Mitternacht (male chorus unaccompanied) 1929 2/94
Eines Narren (SSATB unaccompanied) 1958 8/215
Elementary Training for Musicians (text) 1944 43,9/228
Nine English Songs (S & pf) 1942-44 5/171
Envoy (S & pf) 1942-44 5/171
Erat Joseph et Maria (S/T & pf) 1959 5/162
Erster Schnee (male chorus unaccompanied) 1939 4/152
Es bleibt wohn (SSATB unaccompanied) 1958 8/215
Exiit edictum (S/T & pf) 1960 5/162
The Expiring Frog (B & pf) 1944 5/180
F Year Box/Folder
Film Music: Felix the Cat (player-pf) 1927 2/77
Film Music: Formittagsspuk (player-pf) 1928 2/77
Five Pieces for Piano - The Atonal Cabaret 1921 1/33
Five Songs on Old Texts (SSATB chorus unaccompanied) 1937-38 3/132
Four [Seven?] Pieces (3 trautoniums 1930 2/98
The Four Temperaments (string orchestra & pf solo) 1940 4/160
Frau Musica, opus 45 (cantata) 1928 2/82
Frau Musica (revised version) 1943 5/175
Frauenklage (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
A frog he went a-courting (vc & pf) 1941 5/165
Frühling (SSATB unaccompanied) 1958 8/215
Fuge (2vn) 1931 2/105
Fürst Kraft (male chorus unaccompanied) 1930 2/99
H Year Box/Folder
Die Harmonie der Welt (libretti) 1957 7/211
Die Harmonie der Welt (opera) 1957 7/210
Die Harmonie der Welt (reviews) 1957 8/212
The harp that once thro' Tara's halls (chorus & pf) 1940 4/158
Hérodiade (ballet) 1944 5/179
Hin und Zurück, opus 45a (opera) 1927 2/81
Hindemith's Concept of Ideal Music School (text) 1927 9/235
Hören und Verstehen ungewohnter Musik (text) 1955 10/243
Three Hymns, opus 14 (Bar & pf) 1919 1/23
I Year Box/Folder
Ich will Trauern lassen stehen (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
Image (S & pf) 1955 7/209
In einer Nacht, opus 15 - 15 short pieces (pf) 1919 1/24
In Rembrance of Wilhelm Furtwängler (text) 1955 10/242
In Winter (SATB unaccompanied) 1939 4/149
Ite angeli veloces (cantata) 1953-55 7/206
J Year Box/Folder
Ein Jäger aus Kurpfalz, opus 45 (strings & winds) 1928 2/84
Judaskuss (SSATB unaccompanied) 1958 8/215
Die junge Magd, opus 23b (A, fl, cl, string quartet) 1922 1/35
K Year Box/Folder
Kammermusik No. 1, opus 24 no. 1 (chamber ensemble) 1922 1/36
Kammermusik No. 2, opus 36 no. 1 with pf solo 1924 2/58
Kammermusik No. 3, opus 36 no. 2 with vc solo 1925 2/59
Kammermusik No. 4, opus 36 no. 3 with vn solo 1925 2/60
Kammermusik No. 5, opus 36 no. 4 with va solo 1927 2/61
Kammermusik No. 6, opus 46 no. 1 with va d'amore solo 1927 2/87
Kammermusik No. 7, opus 46 no. 2 with org solo 1927 2/88
Klaviermusik, opus 37 I.: Übung in drei Stücken 1925 2/62
Klaviermusik, opus 37 II.: Reihe kleiner Stücken 1926 2/63
Kleine Kammermusik, opus 24 no. 2 (wdwnd quintet) 1922 1/37
Kleine Klaviermusik, opus 45 - 5 pieces 1928 2/85
Zwei kleine Klavierstücke 1934 3/117
Kleine Sonate (vc & pf) 1942 5/173
Das Köhlerweib (Keller) (voice & pf) 1936 3/130
Konzertmusik für Blasorchester, opus 41 1926 2/69
Konzertmusik, opus 48 (va & chamber orchestra) 1929 2/95
Konzertmusik, opus 49 (pf, brass, 2hp) 1930 2/102
Konzertmusik, opus 50 (string orchestra, brass) 1930 2/103
Konzertstück (2 alto sax) 1933 3/112
Konzertstück (trautonium & string orchestra) 1931 3/106
Kraft fand zu Form (SSATB unaccompanied) 1958 8/215
L Year Box/Folder
Lady's Lament (SSATB unaccompanied) 1937 3/132
Lampe du soir (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
Lehrstück 1929 2/91
Drei leichte Stücke in 1st position (vc & pf) 1938 4/140
Levi exsurgit zephyrus (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
Eine lichte Mitternacht (male chorus unaccompanied) 1929 2/94
Lied des Musterknaben (boys chorus) 1930 2/101
Zwei Lieder (Brentano) (voice & pf) 1936 3/130
Zwei Lieder (Cox) (S & pf) 1955 7/209
Drei Lieder (Nietzsche) (voice & pf) 1939 4/155
Vier Lieder (Busch) 1933 3/115
Vier Lieder (M. Claudius) 1933 3/115
Vier Lieder (Novalis) 1933 3/115
Vier Lieder (Rückert) 1933 3/115
Vier Lieder (Silesius) 1935 3/124
Sechs Lieder (Hölderin) 1933-35 3/114
Sechs Lieder nach alten Texten (SATB unaccompanied) 1923-24 1/55
18 Lieder (S & pf) [the New Haven songs] 1942-43 5/172
Lieder für Singkreise - Rubelli's article 1927 2/72
[see also Song(s)]
Lilacs/A Requiem for those we love 1946 6/185
Lindberghflug - 4 pieces 1929 2/93
The Long Christmas Dinner (opera) 1960 8/219
The Long Christmas Dinner (programs, libretti, etc) 1962 8/220
Ludus minor (cl & vc) 1944 6/182
Ludus Tonalis (pf) 1942 5/169
Ludus Tonalis (sketches) 1942 5/170
Lustige Sinfonietta, opus 4 1916 1/5
M Year Box/Folder
Zwölf Madrigale (SSATB unaccompanied) 1958 8/215
Magisches Rezept (SSATB unaccompanied) 1958 8/215
Mainzer Umzug (STB, narrators, chorus, orchestra) 1962 8/221
March in f minor (pf, 4-hands) 1916 1/7
Das Marienleben, opus 27 (voice & pf) 1922-23 1/43
Das Marienleben, complete (revised version ) 1948 6/191
Das Marienleben, complete (revised version ) 1948 6/192
Das Marienleben, songs with orchestra (revised version 1948 6/193
Marsch über den alten "Schweizerton" (orchestra) 1960 8/218
Martinslied, opus 45 (voices, instruments, audience) 1928 2/86
Mass (mixed chorus a cappella) 1963 8/223
Mathis der Maler (libretti) 1935 3/121
Mathis der Maler (opera) 1933-35 3/118
Mathis der Maler (opera: reviews, cuts, programs) 1935 3/120
Mathis der Maler Symphony 1933 3/119
Methods of Music Theory (text) 1940 10/240
Minimax, Repertorium für Militärmusik (string quartet) 1923 1/54
Mitwelt (SSATB unaccompanied) 1958 8/215
The Moon (S & pf) 1942-44 5/171
Mörder, Hoffnung der Frauen, opus 12 (opera) 1919 1/21
Dreizehn Motetten (S/T & pf) 1940-60 5/162
Musica divina laudes (3-part canon) 1949 7/200
Musical Life in the United States (text) 1949 10/244
N Year Box/Folder
Nach einer alten Skizze (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
Eines Narren (SSATB unaccompanied) 1958 8/215
Neues vom Tage (opera) 1929 2/90
Neues vom Tage (revised version) (opera) 1953 7/207
The New Haven Songs (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
Nine English Songs (S & pf) 1942-44 5/171
Nine Pieces (cl & cb) 1927 2/79
Nine Songs for an American School Songbook 1938 4/139
"1922" Suite (pf) 1922 1/42
Nobilissima Visione (dance legend) 1937 4/137
Nobilissima Visione - suite (orchestra) 1938 4/138
Nun da der Tag (male chorus unaccompanied) 1939 4/146
Nuptiae factae sunt (S/T & pf) 1944 5/162
Das Nusch-Nuschi, opus 20 1920 1/29
Das Nusch-Nuschi, orchestral suite 1920 1/30
O Year Box/Folder
O Grille, sing (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
Oktett (cl, bsn, hn, vn, 2 va, vc, cb) 1958 8/214
Of Household Rule (SSATB unaccompanied) 1937 3/132
Oh, threats of hell (4-part canon) 1945
On a Fly Drinking out of his Cup (S & pf) 1942-44 5/171
On arrange et on compose (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
On hearing "The Last Rose of Summer" (S & pf) 1942-44 5/171
On Mechanical Music (text) 1927 9/236
On the Viola d'Amore (text) 1937 9/238
Orchard (SATB unaccompanied) 1939 4/149
P Year Box/Folder
Pastores loquebantur (S/T & pf) 1944 5/162
Philharmonisches Konzert (orchestra) 1932 3/107
Piano Quintet, opus 7 in e minor 1917 1/9
Piano Suite "1922" 1922 1/42
Two Pieces (org) 1918 1/14
Three Pieces for 5 instruments (pf, cl, tpt, vn, cb) 1925 2/65
Three Pieces, opus 8 (vc & pf) 1917 1/10
Pieces [4] (vc & bsn) 1941 5/166
Four [Seven?] Pieces (3 trautoniums) 1930 2/98
Nine Pieces (cl & cb) 1927 2/79
[see also Stücke]
Pittsburgh Symphony (orchesta) 1958 8/216
Plöner Musiktag 1932 3/108
Q Year Box/Folder
Quartet (cl, vn, vc, pf) 1938 4/141
Quintet (cl & string quartet), opus 30 1923 1/48
R Year Box/Folder
Ranae ad Solam (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
Recitativo e Aria ranatica (B & pf) 1944 5/180
Reflections on Today's Music (text) 1940 10/239
Reger: Psalm 100, revised by Paul Hindemith 1958 8/217
Reihe kleiner Stücken (pf), opus 37 11. 1926 2/63
Requiem for Those We Love/...Lilacs... 1946 6/185
Response upon receiving Balzan Prize in Rome (text) 1963 10/246
Rondo/Triosatz (3 guitars) 1930 2/100
S Year Box/Folder
Sabinchen (radio play) 1930 2/97
Sancta Susanna, opus 21 (opera) 1921 1/31
Schudromane lesen (boys chorus) 1939 2/101
Schulwerk..., opus 44 no. 1 - 9 pieces (vns 1-11) 1927 2/73
Schulwerk..., opus 44 no. 2 - 8 pieces (vns I-II, va) 1927 2/74
Schulwerk..., opus 44 no. 3 - 8 pieces (strings) 1927 2/75
Schulwerk..., opus 44 no. 4 - 5 pieces (string orchestra) 1927 2/76
Der Schwanendreher Concerto (va & small orchestra) 1935 3/123
Sechs Lieder (Hölderlin) 1933-35 3/114
Sechs Lieder nach alten Texten (SATB unaccompanied) 1923-24 1/55
Sehr ruhig (pf) 1929 2/92
Septett (wind instruments) 1948 6/194
Die Serenaden (S, ob, va, vc), opus 35 1924 2/57
Seven Waltzes, opus 6 (pf, 4-hands) 1916 1/8
Since all is passing (SATB unaccompanied) 1939 4/149
Sine musica nulla disciplina (3-part canon) 1946
Sinfonietta in E (orchestra) 1950 7/201
Sing on there in the swamp (high) (S & pf) 1942-44 5/171
Sing on there in the swamp (medium (S & pf) 1942-44 5/171
Sing- und Spielmusiken..., opus 45 1928 2/82
Six Chansons (SATB chorus unaccompanied) 1939 4/149
Sonata (althorn & pf) 1943 5/178
Sonata (bsn & pf) 1938 4/142
Sonata (cb & pf) 1949 7/198
Sonata (cl & pf) 1939 4/150
Sonata (English hn & pf) 1941 5/163
Sonata (fl & pf) 1936 3/129
Canonic Sonata (2 fl), opus 31 no. 3 1923 1/51
Sonata (hn & pf) 1939 4/153
Sonata (4 hn) 1952 7/205
Sonata (hp) 1939 4/151
Sonata (ob & pf) 1938 4/143
Sonata (org) No. 1 1937 4/134
Sonata (org) No. 2 1937 4/135
Sonata (org) No. 3 über alte Volkslieder 1940 4/157
Sonata (pf), opus 17 1920 1/26
Sonata (pf) No. 1 in A 9 (Der Main) 1936 3/126
Sonata (pf) No. 2 in G 1936 3/127
Sonata (pf) No. 3 in B[-flat] 1936 3/128
Sonata (pf, 4-hands) 1938 4/144
Sonata (2 pf) 1942 5/167
Sonata (tbn & pf) 1941 5/164
Sonata (tpt & pf 1939 4/154
Sonata (tuba & pf) 1955 7/208
Sonata (va solo), opus 11 no. 5 1919 1/19
Sonata (va solo), opus 25 no. 1 1922 1/38
Sonata (va solo), opus 31 no. 4 1923 1/52
Sonata (va solo) 1937 3/133
Sonata (va & pf), opus 11 no. 4 1919 1/18
Sonata (va & pf), opus 25 no. 4 1922 1/41
Sonata (va & pf) 1939 4/145
Sonata (va d'amore & pf), opus 25 no. 2 1922 1/39
Sonata (vc solo), opus 25 no. 3 1922 1/40
Sonata (vc & pf), opus 11 no. 3 [opus 11 no. 6] 1919 1/17
Kleine Sonate (vc & pf) 1942 5/173
Sonata (vc & pf) 1948 6/189
Sonata (vn solo), opus 11 no. 6 in c minor 1916 1/20
Sonata (vn solo), opus 31 no. 1 1924 1/49
Sonata (vn solo), opus 31 no. 2 1924 1/50
Sonata (vn & pf), opus 11 no. 1 [opus 11 no. 2] in E-flat 1918 1/15
Sonata (vn & pf), opus 11 no. 2 [opus 11 no. 3] in D 1918 1/16
Sonata (vn & pf) 1935 3/122
Sonata (vn & pf) in C 1939 4/148
Sonata for Ten Instruments [opus 10a] 1917 1/13
A Song of Music (women's chorus & pf/string orchestra) 1940 4/156
Three Songs, opus 9 (S & orchestra) 1917 1/11
Songs in the Aargau Dialect, opus 5 1916 1/6
Five Songs on Old Texts (SSATB chorus unaccompanied) 1937-38 3/132
Nine Songs for an American School Songbook 1938 4/139
Nine English Songs (S & pf) 1942-44 5/171
[see also Lied(er)]
Spielmusik (strings, fls, obs), opus 43 1. 1926-27 2/71
Spielmusik - 4 Lieder für Singkreise, opus 43 11. 1926-27 2/71
Springtime (SATB unaccompanied) 1939 4/149
Sterbende Gewässer (address) 1963 9/234
Die Stiefmutter (male chorus unaccompanied) 1939 4/146
String Quartet No. 1, opus 2 in C 1915 1/3
String Quartet No. 2, opus 10 in f minor 1918 1/12
String Quartet No. 3, opus 16 in C 1920 1/25
String Quartet No. 4, opus 22 1921 1/32
String Quartet No. 5, opus 32 1923 1/53
String Quartet No. 6 in E-flat 1943 5/174
String Quartet No. 7 1945 6/184
String Trio No. 1, opus 34 1924 2/56
String Trio No. 2. 1933 3/111
Drei Stücke/Etuden (2 vn) 1931 2/105
Drei leichte Stücke in 1st position (vc & pf) 1938 4/140
[see also Pieces]
Suite französischer Tänze (small orchestra) 1948 6/190
Suite "1922" (pf) 1922 1/42
Nobilissima Visione - suite (orchestra) 1938 4/138
A Swan (SATB unaccompanied) 1939 4/149
Symphonia Serena (orchestra) 1946 6/186
Symphonic Metamorphosis on Themes by Weber (orchestra) 1943 5/177
Symphonie "Die Harmonie der Welt" 1951 7/203
Symphonie "Mathis der Maler" 1933 3/119
Pittsburgh Symphony (orchestra) 1958 8/216
Symphony in E-flat (orchestra) 1940 5/161
Symphony in E-flat (concert band) 1952 7/202
Symphonische Tänze (orchestra) 1937 4/136
T Year Box/Folder
Tauch deine (SSATB unaccompanied) 1958 8/215
Thema mit vier Variationen (string orchestra & pf solo) 1940 4/160
Three Hymns, opus 14 (Bar & pf) 1919 1/23
Three Pieces for 5 instruments (pf, cl, tpt, vn, cb) 1925 2/65
Three Pieces, opus 8 (vc & pf) 1917 1/10
Three Songs, opus 9 (S & orchestra) 1917 1/11
To a Snowflake (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
Toccata, opus 40 (player-pf) 1926 2/67
Der Tod (male chorus) 1932 3/110